I've made 494 YouTube videos,
and I've had so many of them bomb,
crash, do nothing.
But I just started two channels,
and I'm making a short course
on everything I've learned.
But I thought in this video,
how quickly could I give
you 40 lessons that could save you the
years that I wasted so that
you could accomplish more than what I've
accomplished in a shorter period of time
and eat less shit? First of all,
why should you listen to me?
Because I
have one of these. No,
you can get one of them from having a few
viral reels.
Don't be impressed by those.
But do make sure if you have one,
that it's in the
background. Rule number one,
no one cares about you.
And I know this can sound really horrible
and morbid to begin with, but think about
this.
Everyone just cares about themselves.
It's such a beautiful thing
that you can understand and learn.
It'll save you so much time,
not just on YouTube,
but every single social media
platform.
People are just out for themselves.
And you think, what about people that
are generous, that give to charity?
Philanthropic.
They're doing it because it makes them
feel better.
Even when I buy dinner for my friends,
they think I'm being kind. I'm not.
I do not enjoy people buying dinner for
me.
It makes me feel uncomfortable.
I did not do it because I like you people.
I did it because it makes me feel better.
So when creating a video,
especially the packaging,
but especially what you talk
about in the video,
it must do something for other people.
So even if you want to talk about yourself
and the weight that you lost, the muscle
you built,
even the way you communicate has to be
changed.
So if you did want to lose those five
pounds of excess weight,
I would suggest that
you do these things because they've worked
for me.
And it's imperative
that you stay on top of your progressive
overload so you can
get the results.
If you just talk about yourself in
content, people leave.
If you can make videos, even right now,
I don't think you should give a shit about
anything that I've done
and accomplished or even
that Silver Play Button.
Just stay tuned for what you can get out
of this.
If I make this video about you,
by the end of it,
you'll think I'm a legend.
But anyway, let's move on. Number two,
title and thumbnail first.
Title and thumbnail first. In front of me,
I have the title for this video.
That's how I know how many videos I've
done, and a proposed idea of a thumbnail.
So many of you,
I know you make a banging video,
then you get to the end, you sit
there and go, "Hmm, what's title
and thumbnail?"
[mumbles] Do that first because the first
thing you
say in the video kind of has to pay off
the title and thumbnail.
Because if you're going to build
curiosity, which is what a good title and
thumbnail should do,
you kind of got to allude to what's coming
in the introduction
to the video,
and if there's anything disjointed between
those, people will leave.
Number three,
strategize the first thing that you say.
When I was about to make this video,
I actually said it too long, so I
pressed stop, and then I hit record again,
and I started again.
The very first words
that come out of my mouth
were about the amount of videos I've
made, an appeal to authority.
We had the Silver Play Button,
another appeal to
authority. The amount of lessons
that I was going to show you being 40.
I also said that I spent a few days
and weeks putting together a course,
and I'm
going to put it into a succinct short
video so you can learn all of that.
So I'm raising the stake saying, "Hey,
I've just spent weeks doing things,
and I'm
going to give it all to you in a matter of
minutes for free." You want to know
what's coming,
and you want to know in the shortest
period possible.
So I need to really strategize the first
words that come out of my mouth.
Which takes me on to point four,
strategizing the first thing you see.
The first thing you should see
is a pretty good setup,
color grading quite good,
microphone out of sight,
lighting quite nice.
Products in the background, again,
another appeal to authority.
But me holding the Silver Play Button
was kind of alluding to what
was happening.
That is a sign of success on YouTube,
although, a rubbish one, and if it's
something that you're working towards,
you might feel an emotive connection
between
me, what I'm saying, and that.
Lesson number five,
the rule of 100 videos.
I know it can sound crass
and kind of a bit bland,
but you should be focusing as
quick as you can to make
that first 100 videos.
Because some you think
are going to do so well,
they're going to bomb.
Others you pretty much think are rubbish,
and they do much better than others.
But the repetitions, making thumbnails,
trying titles, talking to camera.
Although strategy is such a big part of
it, volume is also an
integral part of it.
If you want to get better at golf,
play more golf.
You want to get better at chess,
play more chess.
You want to get better at chin-ups,
do more chin-ups.
You understand where I'm going with this.
Just put your head down, blinkers on,
do 100 videos.
I did 100 videos in 100 days. It
was exhausting.
99 of them ate shit,
but I'm so grateful to it because every
single time, I
learnt a little thing about YouTube,
and that's what this is, learning.
Number six, shorts
and long videos sit on different
algorithms.
So you can get your shorts going on
YouTube and get loads of really good
views, and
then your subscriber rate's going up.
Then you post your first long video,
and you spent two weeks making it, and it
bombs, and no one sees it.
It's gone to a cold algorithm.
You need to build it up.
You need to warm it up.
Think of it like having two girlfriends at
the same time.
Just because you're really good
and cozy with one,
you're taking her for dinner and
schmoozing her a lot doesn't mean you can
just turn up at the other one's house and
be like, "Yo,
give us a blouse." You got to do the same
process over there.
You got to do the very first things
that got you the blouse with the first
one, with the second one. Two girls,
same time.
Or just date one and be monogamous,
and it's probably better.
And if you were, pick long form videos.
So don't just expect because you're
chucking out funny reels
that your long form's
going to get all the exposure.
It doesn't make sense.
Mostly because people that
are good at shorts aren't good at long
form and vice
versa. Rule number seven,
everyone wants to leave all the time in
your video.
And if you take too long,
you labor your point,
you disrespect someone's
time, they're just going to leave.
Think of it all the time,
like someone's just thinking,
"Do I really want to sit
here and watch this?" They're kind of
finger flickering over the screen, and
if you
just don't put the respect into their
attention and time, they will go.
Anything you can cut out a video
and it still makes sense, cut it out.
If you can make a 15-minute video a
10-minute video without losing any,
make it 10
minutes.
Consider everyone wanting to leave all the
time.
Don't give them the opportunity to.
But don't do it when you say, "Oh,
in this video,
we're going to look at three
things and wait till the last thing
because in the last thing we're going to
talk
about,
you're going to understand something
you've never understood." Bored, gone.
Number eight, social hacking.
Sometimes you're a small channel,
you're a small
creator, it is worth taking something
that is familiar with people and
using it. For instance, on mine,
did videos about Athletic Greens,
did videos about
Steven Bartlett and Joe Rogan in the
podcast space,
did things about Liver King.
If there was ever anyone in my niche
that I could talk about
that had a familiar
face,
I would do it because people would be
gravitated to them more than me.
However,
if I did a good point of making a video
about that thing and that subject,
whether it's Whoop, AG1, whatever,
you get subscribers from it.
Although you might be the front
and center of the show,
sometimes you do need to
look at things and popular products
that you can combine with what you want to
say
so you can get that exposure. Number nine,
the outdated Derral Eves approach.
In 2017, '18, doing this
worked. But guess what?
It doesn't work now. You look like a pleb.
You look shit.
Think about something in the thumbnail
being the hero.
The 10 secrets Rolex don't want you to
know.
How Nutonic built a $20 million empire.
What they don't want you to know about the
new iOS.
And think about something being the hero
of the image, whether the
hero is the transformation with you before
and after, whether the hero is the
product that you're talking about,
whether the hero is the person you're
disagreeing with. Whatever it is,
just don't do the old
You're like a knob. Number 10,
tell stories.
Human brain, well, it loves stories.
For instance, if I did a video saying,
"Is intermittent fasting really that
good for you?" Versus,
"I didn't eat for 72 hours to prove the
internet wrong."
Suddenly you know there's a story. Oh,
why didn't he eat for 72 hours?
What was he trying to prove the internet
wrong with?
At least then I could build the curiosity
to at least get the click.
And then in the click,
people out online are saying
that not eating is good for
your health, and I disagree,
and I've gone on a mission,
and I even didn't eat for
three days.
And not eating for three days
was raising the stakes, and it was
miserable. It's on my big YouTube channel.
Wouldn't recommend it.
But everything can be turned into a story.
Again,
I was going to do a video on a calorie
deficit and how to lose fat, but
instead, I did a video on eating
and burning 5,000 calories in a day.
And actually, that
is a video about total daily energy
expenditure bundled up into
a story.
Because just by reading the title,
they know what's happening.
Then in the introduction,
I show them me running and walking
and cycling on a
bike and eating and scoffing,
and you turned it into a story.
So whatever it is, often this
is the thing you want to talk about in a
video.
What Trojan horse can you pack it in
and stick it in within?
For instance,
rather than doing a video on jujitsu,
I'm planning on doing a video
on Bondi Beach called "Fighting Strangers
to Prove Jujitsu Works." Again, you know
exactly what it's about. You click on it,
the introduction is, some people say
jujitsu wouldn't work.
I'm here on Bondi Beach,
and I'm going to fight anyone.
And if they submit me,
they get to win $1,000. Does jujitsu work?
We're going to find out. Story. Number 11,
evergreen.
There are some videos on YouTube
that just continue to churn sales
and sales and
sales and sales and sales.
I did a video about personal training.
It, for nine months, 10 months,
did nothing, then it took off,
and it's making
me about $200, $300 a day in revenue.
So there is a world
that you could potentially imagine having
so much good
content on your channel
that you could walk away for months on
end, and it would
continue to bring you leads.
That does not happen on other platforms
like it
happens on YouTube.
We're starting to see a bit of a trend on
LinkedIn, but that's
for another video altogether,
where a lot of content on LinkedIn
is now two to
three weeks old, which is showing us
that there's a maturing process happening
there.
So even if you don't see attribution of
good amounts of engagement on
LinkedIn straight away, don't fret,
it could be coming. Number 12.
And I must say thank you to Ed Lawrence,
who, yes, two videos ago, I was
disagreeing with. He
was great at grabbing me
and pulling my head out and going,
"You don't get paid by YouTube.
You pay yourself." For instance,
this video, no
AdSense, not interested.
A couple of dollars from Google? Nice.
Instead,
I'd rather have links to my description,
give away free assets as a lead
magnet,
and give away links to paid programs where
they can just go in there, sign
up with me,
and instead of me getting a few dollars
from Google, I can earn
thousands from people joining my programs.
That is a huge change in direction.
Instead of thinking of getting viral on
YouTube to earn AdSense,
think about having
a business that YouTube can be a marketing
department that puts eyeballs on it.
Once you can unattach from that,
your whole relationship to your business
is vastly
different. Number 13, community wall.
Some people still don't know
that there are posts
that you can put on your
community wall with text and image.
Now, what I would say to you
is those of you looking to grow your
LinkedIn, this is
something I'm doing recently.
I've just grown my following by about
20,000
followers.
I now go to LinkedIn first thing in the
morning, create a post.
Then my posts that do well,
I repurpose onto my YouTube community
wall.
If they do well there,
they go onto my business Instagram.
Think of your content strategy depending
on what you're doing, maybe written with
image and video. Which is best?
Up to you to find out.
But the community wall should be seen a
bit like LinkedIn, bit like Twitter, bit
like Threads.
Although after the atrocities
that I saw on Threads the
day after Charlie Kirk's death,
I'm never going back on
that platform ever again.
But anyway. Number 14, thumbnail quality.
If you're going to do a thumbnail,
try not to take a screen grab.
And I'm being a hypocrite right now
because a lot of my videos at the moment
are
screen grabs. And again, I must credit Ed.
This is something
that he's taught me about.
I'll put a link to him in the description.
He's actually technically a competitor of
mine, but I've learnt so much from him
that I feel guilty
if I don't attribute the things I've
learnt from him.
And if that means you join his program
instead of mine, so be it.
There's kind of two battles of thought
here.
If I was doing a video about yellow tint
Burberry glasses, I
would say, "Declan, come here,
grab the camera.
I want to get the 50 mil lens,
and I want a good little picture of that."
However,
there's something about there being a
disjointedness between the very
first thing you see in a thumbnail
and the video you're watching.
Let's say I'm in the studio right now,
but the thumbnail is me on the beach.
You're like, "Oh,
James on the beach." You click it,
and you're in a dark little
room. You're like, "Oh,
that isn't what I clicked on." So for me,
sometimes I am
sacrificing the quality of the image
and use a screen grab because I want that
familiarity between the packaging
and the video.
But if you look to any of the other videos
on this channel, there's some high-res
images, me in front of the car,
me holding a book.
Where possible,
I will always opt for a high-res image.
So thumbnail quality matters. And again,
I've sometimes spent an hour and a
half making a thumbnail for a video,
and it's always the videos where I put
that
huge amount of time into creating a
thumbnail, they way outperform.
One of my Prime videos,
I had to order 100 cans of Prime.
Then I had to wait three weeks for it to
get delivered.
But for the thumbnail, it was worth it.
For another thumbnail,
I bought like 140 cans of Coke Zero.
Again, stacked them all up. Worth it.
You can raise stakes in a thumbnail.
Raise stakes in a thumbnail. Because
when they see straight away, the cognitive
part of their brain goes, "Oh shit,
that guy went and bought 120 cans just for
an
image to represent his video.
If he's going to go to
that much effort there, he's
probably not going to cut corners in the
video." Number 15, content buckets.
If you go to MrBeast's channel,
you will see that the majority of videos
sit into a
bucket. 24 hours buried alive.
24 hours underwater.
24 hours in space.
Then there'll be last one to take the hand
off a private jet
gets to keep it.
Last person to take the hand off the
Lamborghini gets to keep it.
These are all different segments
or content buckets.
Then there'll be another.
Cheapest hotel versus most expensive
hotel.
Cheapest private jet versus most expensive
private jet.
Cheapest bunker versus most expensive
bunker. These are buckets and silos.
So whatever industry you're in,
you can bucket your content.
Maybe in fitness, it could be fat loss,
muscle growth, debunking myths,
reacting to
something. Think about getting buckets
and strategies so that when you are coming
to making content,
you can think of what you're doing.
So for instance, in my buckets,
my next one is going to be critiquing
people's
content. So you'll notice
that once every 10 days,
I end up critiquing people's
content, giving them feedback,
tearing them a new asshole from a place of
love.
By the way, if you want that,
there's a link in the description.
You send it there, and then in
that next video that I'm doing,
I will go through
your stuff and critique it.
So everything goes into a content bucket.
If you do it that way,
you can sometimes just have an easier time
being creative
with what you're going to do next.
Number 16, tracking links.
Again,
this video is going to seem like I'm
wanking off Ed.
He's a good friend of mine. RevTrack
is what the majority of us are
using. That's now his business as well.
I'll put a link to
that in the description.
It's bloody good.
Tracking links in videos shows us where
we're getting money from
and where we're not, and pretty much
that can give us the peace of mind that
although a video might have got an eight
out of ten on YouTube, it could be a heist
rev video. Again,
sometimes I'll create videos
and I'll think, "My God, that's
doing badly." Boom.
Someone buys $3,000 products. Boom.
Someone buys another one of them.
And I'm like, "Wow,
that video only got 1,500
views,
but it's made me $6,000." So tracking
links are great because you can
see although a video's not getting
that huge amount of reach
and huge amount of
views,
it could still be potentially giving you
lots of driven sales, data,
traffic, whatever. And the quicker
that you can dissociate views from success
and
actually people buying your product being
success, the better you can hone in on
what's working for your business
and what isn't.
Number 17, click-through rate
and average view duration.
Some people think, "Oh, this video, why
is it not doing well?
It's got a really high click-through
rate." Well,
if it's got a high click-through
rate,
often YouTube's not pushing it out wide.
And alternatively,
if you have a video go viral,
your click-through rate bombs.
So these metrics are not
that important to look at.
Average view duration, again,
would probably be a better one to look at
because if
people are staying
and watching long periods of your video,
that's a metric of
success, not the click-through rate.
So I'd say YouTube's at a ten score
rating, bit poo. Click-through rate,
bit poo.
Average view duration, more important.
Don't get caught up on those metrics
because if a video does shit
or does really
well,
it massively influences those things. 18,
channel branding.
What you call the channel represent
yourself.
I'm James Smith, to the point
that I've got two channels both called
James Smith.
Because that's who I am, that's my brand.
So for some of you,
you're not Active Health PT,
you're not Back Pain Specialist
01. You are insert name.
And although we've got like MrBeast
and we've got
who else? People that have aliases online.
Trust me, for the majority of you,
99% of you, just your brand is you.
Represent yourself,
put your name in there,
and don't use your Fortnite game tag.
Number 19, browse versus search.
A lot of people think that your videos
are getting
discovered from search.
If you go into your analytics on YouTube,
you can see that
actually the majority of videos get found
through browse.
So when you're creating concepts
and ideas,
don't think about someone searching
what is the best stretch For the pec
major.
Instead, think about something
that someone could browse across
and be unable to
leave.
Think about someone scrolling through
their YouTube, going past your video,
then going, "Hold on," and going back
and bookmarking it or downloading it for a
flight.
So that pec stretch could be three ways to
stretch your chest you've never
even heard of. Making that up. Number 20,
channel trailer.
So the channel trailer
is the video that's going to sit there on
your channel when
people get there.
If you go into your analytics again,
you can easily see which
video grows your channel the most,
gets the most subscribers. Put
that in there.
Or go to your rev track
or your tracking links
and look at the video that makes you
the most money. Put that in there.
Put in a video that gives you the success
that
you want.
Don't just put the one in there with the
most views.
Number 21,
occasionally make very long videos.
And if you don't believe me,
any of you out there
that have made a mixture of good
videos, bundle them all together,
put them out there, and even
if it's like a
two-hour video or a three-hour video,
just trust me.
The average view duration on that
is sometimes mega.
People might put it on
when they're driving,
or they might put it on while they're
cooking,
and you might actually accrue such a long
period of time of people
watching. Again,
why livestreams can do really well.
Do not be afraid to make really long
videos once in a
while because you can kind of
play into that average view duration,
and YouTube goes, well,
usually people watch
this person's stuff for 12 minutes,
but this video,
they're watching it for 19.
It must be good. Boom, more traffic,
algorithmic, bosh.
Twenty two, ChatGPT. A lot of people
are saying, "Oh, you've got to use this.
You've got to use that." Keep it simple.
If there are competitors and outliers,
sometimes you can just copy their
transcript, put it into ChatGPT. What
was in this video? What
are the highlights?
Have a little look through.
This means that when you're doing
competitor homework
and looking at what's doing well for other
people, rather than sitting there
through half-hour videos
and getting bored,
you can nab the transcript from five to
10 different videos, put them all into AI,
and go, what is the general theme of all
of these?
Then you can go copy all the comments,
put the comments in there, and go,
what do people like
and dislike about these videos?
Suddenly,
you get your script to your video
that you've planned and made out.
You put that in there and go,
from all the things you've seen in the
comments and
all the other things there,
is there anything missing from my video?
What would you put in? Then
if you wanted to go a step further,
you could say, in
my writing style,
could you expand into those points
that you thought I should have
in my video?
That's why I think it's pretty good.
Which brings me on to number 23,
scripting.
You can script a video word for word,
but sometimes just put all the ideas you
want
into a Google Doc. If you work in a team,
send it to other people in your team.
Have I missed anything out? Again,
you go back to ChatGPT.
Is there anything you think I'm missing
out?
But sometimes a Google Doc
is great because then I can put things in
there,
thumbnails, titles, whatever,
send it to my editor,
or even send it to anyone in my
team,
and they can look through my ideation.
They might say,
"Why don't you put this in?
Why don't you put that in?" Or,
"I love the thumbnail.
Have you thought about this for a title?"
Twenty-four, don't do vlogs.
If you want to do well on YouTube,
it's from 500 videos, solve problems.
Because the vlog, no one gives a fuck.
That's rule number one, right?
Now,
unless your vlog solves a problem of
someone being bored, fair
enough.
But not many of you have lives
that interesting.
You'll even notice that Logan Paul,
one of the vlog kings, even their titles,
him
and Jake Paul,
are still very specific clickbaity titles,
and they usually have a
story. It might be masqueraded as a vlog,
but it's not. It's a story being told.
Because vlogs are very hard to package
for.
And if people don't know what they're
getting, unless you're Mike Thurston,
they're
not just going to watch you live day to
day.
But if you solve someone's problem,
that's going to draw in the people
that want
that problem solved,
and then you can be quite creative
and actually quite targeted
because surely those problems you solve
are going to be similar into the niche
that
you're solving, right?
Even this video right now,
the problems I'm solving here,
probably for small solo entrepreneur
businesses that would love to
learn five years of YouTube mistakes in
one video.
You guys would be perfect for my business.
Again, links in the description.
See what I did there? But again,
if I just did a vlog,
I could just attract random
people,
and it would just not be specific enough.
I'd rather have 5,000 views from this type
of video than 100,000 views from a vlog.
Twenty-five, timestamps. On some videos,
you'll notice that there's little
timestamps down the bottom,
which I will do for this video.
Again, back in the day,
we used to have to go through,
get your editor, blah, blah,
blah, blah. But now, transcript, ChatGPT,
give me timestamps.
Now, the timestamps are two-folded.
One,
some people might want to skip through to
a part of the video.
Let's say you're doing a tech review on
the new Yacht-Master
Titanium, right?
And you're going to compare it to a
Submariner or whatever it is,
right? Some people
are going to skip through
and just want to go to the conclusion.
Or you're doing it on the Road Active GO
Mic or whatever it is.
Some people just want the conclusion.
They don't want everything else,
the nuts in the box.
However, although
that timestamp can seem like a really good
thing to put into your
videos, just consider this.
You're sometimes offering people the
opportunity to
skip ahead,
and that isn't always a good thing for
retention. It can't be.
Because what's YouTube going to say
if 60% of people skip past this part of
the
video? It's going, well,
that bit's obviously shit.
So with a pinch of salt,
depending on your niche,
timestamps can be good or
terrible. Number 26, livestreams.
Livestreams, massively underrated.
I need to do more of them.
They bang sales.
And sometimes the videos
are quite well curated, like this one,
we're chopping all
the gaps in between me thinking
or whatever.
In a livestream,
people get to see you for who you are
and your idiosyncrasies.
What makes you you is not hidden.
They can see it.
They can see the way you interact with
people.
I would love to,
and I might even trial going to one
livestream a week.
I built my business off the back of
livestreams,
so I cannot promote those enough.
Honestly, if you can ever go live
and you have the luxury to do it, do it.
Number 27, call to actions.
You'll notice that
if you look at your video and your
retention graph, even the best of you,
the majority of people leave towards the
end.
So leaving a call to action to the end
means that 70% of the people that watch
your video are never even going to know
your call to action.
So get them in earlier.
You'll notice I've probably got one in
within the first
three minutes here, then again,
another one maybe halfway through.
Do not leave call to actions to the end.
Get them in.
Say to people, "Look,
I've got free assets in my description,
and there's links to
my paid programs in there as well.
Choose one of those things.
Give me a damn email address.
I'll put you into a sales funnel,
and you can see how
I do it." That was me telling you,
but also at the same time, telling you,
description. Come on. Number 28,
end cards.
I used to not know what end cards are,
but at the end of this, I'm going to point
to an area. And in YouTube,
you go to Editor, you go Add Video,
Probably best
for viewer,
or if you want to end a video with a hook,
you can also end it with a
hook, as in, "Oh, and if you
are someone that didn't know how to
perform the
Heimlich maneuver on an 82-year-old
grandma of four,
then you're going to want to
click this video so you can find out." End
cards are great because they can create
binge effects.
So you can send them from video A to video
B, then video B to video
C, video C to video D. You get the gist.
Number 29, inside that editor,
the tools are now getting pretty good,
so that if
you're looking at your retention graph
and there's a little bit where it just
bombs, you can go in there and cut it out.
There's some personal information
or a number plate
that you didn't want to be in a
video. You can go in, you can blur.
The editing tool is getting very good,
so you
can go in and make changes to a video once
it's been published.
Some people cut the bad bits out their
videos after it's gone up.
I've even cut the introduction out of a
few of my videos. Improves retention.
The score of that video
is only going to improve.
YouTube will put it out to more people
sometimes. Number 30, screen recorder.
If you ever want to show people what you
do on your laptop, go into QuickTime, go
Screen Recorder, MacBook Audio.
That clap is going to create a spike in
your audio and your camera,
a spike in your
audio there. You line them up, and bosch.
You've now got the ability to show people
what you're doing on your desktop.
In the edit, you can cut between them.
Number 31, edit on desktop.
There's I don't know how many people with
a silver play button that are editing
their videos on their phone.
Do it on a computer. Use DaVinci Resolve.
I'm actually bringing out a course for
that very soon.
Premiere Pro, also very good. Final Cut
is also excellent. They're all good.
Edit on a computer.
It's one of those things
that it's just going to improve your
editing speed. And even if it's only 10,
15 minutes quicker per edit, that shit
adds up. Number 32,
thumbnail split testing.
If you're unsure with thumbnails
or styles or whatever it is,
you can now put three
into YouTube. Before,
you had to use thumbnailtest.co.uk
or thumbnailtest.com, but
now you can do it in YouTube.
Choose three different designs.
Not if you're brand new to YouTube, but
if you've got over 2,000 subscribers,
100%. Try different words,
different angles, different lighting.
I even A/B split tested holding a syringe
in one hand or reversing the image and
having it in the other,
and it made an impact to click through.
Test your thumbnails, see what works,
and learn.
Number 33, Thumbsup.tv.
It's a website you can go in,
put your thumbnail in, put
your title, see how it looks.
A lot of channels,
even massive channels with really
big followers, have got titles that
are too long,
and it ends up being "dot dot
dot" before the end of it.
You're better off your title being too
short than too
long. And don't put, "Episode two,
training with this," then your
name in the title.
You're just making the title look crap.
On Netflix,
when there's a new season of something,
it just has the name of the
season. It doesn't go, "Season two,
introducing Mindhunter.
Season two." No.
If there's too much there,
people get overwhelmed, and get out
of it. Number 34, using a good camera
is a good thing, but the
iPhone's pretty good.
You can record on those.
You can record sideways.
You can even plug them into your Mac so
you can see on your computer how you're
recording. Stepping up,
if you're on the move a lot
and you're going around and
documenting and on the move,
use the DJI Pocket Osmo 3.
When it comes to getting an entry-level
Sony, the ZV-E10 Mark 2 is also
very, very good. This is an FX3,
but you do not need an FX3.
I had like 400,000 subs before I got an
FX3.
Which brings me on to number 35, audio.
Get good audio. It's really important.
You could use the Joe Rogan mic, which
is called a Shure SM7B.
That will need to be powered through a
type of amp.
There is also some type of technology
between the mic and the computer called a
Cloudlifter. Now,
before you get overwhelmed,
that gives you cleaner audio.
The amps will do that,
like a RODECaster mix deck
if you get a RODECaster 2, if
this is sounding too much.
Shure also have a worse version that can
go in as a USB mic. Ultimately,
audio does get pretty complex.
For those of you who'll see in my earlier
videos, I clip on a DJI.
RODE used to be the dogs. And RODE
are great when it comes to directional
microphones.
I think their clip-on ones are a bit naff.
DJI, unreal, and there's a brand
that some of you might not have heard of
called
Hollyland. Hollyland are also exceptional.
So I'd say Hollyland entry level,
DJI entry level.
I would say
as far as getting a podcast mic, Shure
are going to be the best,
S-H-U-R-E. And then
if you really want to scope it up
and get a mic that people
can't even see in it,
you're going to look into Sennheiser
territory, like the MKH
416 right over here. Audio
is important because a lot of your videos
are
more like podcasts than they are videos.
People are listening in.
If this went black and white,
you wouldn't really care.
But if the audio got cut out,
you'd be like,
"I'm not listening to this." Which
brings me on to number 36, lighting.
I've got two lights on me now.
I've got a big honeycomb light here,
giving me a bit of a Rembrandt.
Then that little shine on the face
is coming from a hair light to my side.
We have got some glow lights down there,
but they're not really making too much of
an issue.
We're going to have to change
that in a little bit.
But one light is all it takes.
Don't need much more than that.
Here, also in this room, we
are controlling the light.
So I've got blackout curtains. Actually,
those curtains there are
acoustic curtains,
so they're killing the reverb from my
voice echoing around the
room. This room cost £35,000.
My content before was sick.
It was fire, don't worry, but still,
this makes it better.
Them curtains, £1,500. Now,
I'm not sure if I'm getting old,
or it's the economy, or it's inflation,
but £1,500?
I once traveled Southeast Asia for six
months. I spent three grand.
I've just spent half of
that on [censored] curtains.
Although I make incredibly good money,
that still hurts. It still hurts.
Number 37, premieres.
You can create premieres.
So if you've made a big YouTube piece you
want to share with people, they can all
tune in and watch it together,
which means you've all got to watch it
before the
video goes live. Do they work?
Are they good? Sure. Do I use them?
Not really.
38, new channels. If you
are going to diversify what you do,
rather than confusing
your audience on one channel,
sometimes you need to create a new one.
This one is the second channel.
I had to start from zero.
Yes, that sucked, but at the same time,
it also just gave me the opportunity to
work into a niche because me doing B2B
here and me doing B2C in the other
channels,
they're different.
So I started a new channel, and it
was very, very good.
Number 39, finding outliers.
When you have competitors,
you should all know your
top five to 10 competitors, even
if you think they're bellends.
You should be keeping an eye on videos
they have that are outliers.
Don't just look to their most popular
video with the most views, because
that could
be five years old,
and the trend could have died.
If you use plug-ins like vidIQ, which
are for free,
you can actually have a look at
what videos are trending for people at any
given point, because it could be a video
from three months ago,
and it's just started picking up traction.
Why?
It doesn't matter.
Maybe you want to use that as an outlier.
And then number 40,
the most important out of all of them,
emulation.
You should be looking to find ideas off
things that have worked already.
We spoke about Ed before,
really good friend of mine,
also an investor in Nu Tonic,
which I'm very grateful for.
I actually did go to his channel,
and I looked at what
is the most viewed video
that he's ever done, and it
was a video on all the lessons
that he'd learned from YouTube.
So I'm not copying his videos.
I actually didn't even watch it.
I did put it into ChatGPT,
just to have a little
look.
But I created a list of 40 things
that were completely different.
The only ones that we have as crossovers
are things that I learned through working
with him. Because why try
and come up with an idea for a video on my
own when I
know it worked well for him?
And maybe at some point,
he will look at my videos,
see what's working well for me,
and do the same.
And whichever one of us makes more money
will pay for dinner when I see him in
Dubai, which will be him every night.
If you have any questions about YouTube,
ask them below.
There are going to be links in the
description. And wow, is YouTube psychic?
Because it thinks you should watch this
video, and I think YouTube's right.
So click that, and we can go into what
was number 26, the binge effect.
Thanks for watching. Oh,
we haven't actually set that up yet.
There might be a link for the YouTube
course waitlist. I don't know.
Check the description. Bye-bye.